OLIVER ROICK

\$\subset\$ +44 7860 803902 \$\alpha\$ oliverroick.de \$\subset\$ oliver.roick@gmail.com \$\overline{\over

I am a geographer who builds database-driven web applications that assist in collecting, visualising and analysing geographic information.

I have experience in data modelling, designing and implementing web APIs to disseminate geographic data and maps. I have also built browser-based applications to collect, manage and visualise geographic information.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

■ SINCE SEPTEMBER 2013

Developer, Extreme Citizen Science Research Group, University College London, United Kingdom

- Designed, implemented and maintained GeoKey, a platform for participatory mapping; including data modelling, API design and documentation, and testing.
- Led software developers of the research group through agile project management. Created and introduced guidelines for software development, code quality and testing.
- Advised the social enterprise "Mapping for Change" in designing and developing the new Community Maps platform.
 Implemented automated data migration between the old and new system.

APRIL 2010 TO AUGUST 2013

Research Assistant, Chair of GIScience, Ruprecht-Karls-University Heidelberg, Germany

- Conducted scientific studies, which focussed on analysis and visualisation of user-generated geographic information, such as OpenStreetMap and location-based social networks.
- Led the re-implementation of client-side components of OpenRouteService, a web-based routing service based on OpenStreetMap and OGC OpenLS specification.
- Design and implementation of OSMatrix (back-end and frontend), including data processing and visualisation of results via a custom Tile Map Service and a web API.
- Created lab courses and held seminars for graduate students, teaching aspects web-based GIS.
- As head of the local organisation committee, I helped organise FOSSGIS 2011, the leading German speaking user conference for open-source GIS.

KEY SKILLS

- Designing and building database-driven web applications
- · Geographic data visualisation
- · API design and documentation
- · Data modeling
- Agile project management
- · Test-driven development

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- JavaScript
- Python
- Java

FRAMEWORKS

- NodeJS
- Django
- · OpenLayers2
- Leaflet
- D3
- · jQuery
- Mapnik
- Geoserver

DATABASES

- · Postgres + PostGIS
- MySQL

VERSION CONTROL

- SVN
- Git + Github

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

■ SEPTEMBER 2008 TO MARCH 2010

Research Assistant, Chair of Geoinformatics, Friedrich-Schiller-University Jena, Germany

- Designed and implemented a mobile application for in-field meta data management of hydrologic gaging stations.
- Designed and implemented an API to synchronise collected data with the River Basin Information System (RBIS).

ACADEMIC EDUCATION

OCTOBER 2001 TO JUNE 2008

Diploma (equivalent to Master's degree) Studies at Friedrich-Schiller-University Jena, Germany

- · Majors: Geography, Computer Science and Geology
- Diploma thesis at International Institute for Geo-Information Science and Earth Observation (ITC), Enschede, The Netherlands; Thesis title: "Using open standards for browserbased integration and visualisation of geo-spatial data"

CERTIFICATES

BCS Foundation Certificate in Agile Project Management

References are available upon request.